<?xml version="1.0"?>
<info xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
      xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://apps.nextcloud.com/schema/apps/info.xsd">
    <id>scholiq</id>
    <name lang="en">Scholiq</name>
    <name lang="nl">Scholiq</name>
    <summary lang="en">Open-source LVS + LMS for Nextcloud — student tracking, course creation, certification, and compliance training.</summary>
    <summary lang="nl">Open-source LVS + LMS voor Nextcloud — leerlingvolgsysteem, cursusbeheer, certificering en compliance-training.</summary>
    <description lang="en"><![CDATA[Scholiq combines a leerlingvolgsysteem (LVS) for primary, secondary, and higher education with a leeromgeving / LMS for corporate L&D and government employee training.

**v0.1 wedge — Compliance training**

- Annual AVG / BIO / NIS2 / Cyberbeveiligingswet refresher courses
- Bulk-enrol all employees in mandatory training
- Capture signed attestations per learner
- Detect upcoming certificate expiries
- Real-time coverage percentage per regulation
- Audit-pack export with immutable evidence log
- External-training bulk recording with officer verification and linked credential issuance
- School-year rollover wizard (propose mapping, side-effect-free preview)
- IMS QTI 2.x / 3.0 and Common Cartridge item-bank import
- Open Badges 3.0 credential issuance and public verification endpoint

**Later phases**

- K-12 leerlingvolgsysteem (Phase 2): BRON/ROD, UWLR, OSO, Edukoppeling, SchoolID/ECK iD pseudonymisation, OPP cycle, PTA grading, DigiD parent flow — a generic data-exchange job queue with an OSO parent-approval gate already exists, but no BRON/ROD, OSO, or SURFconext OpenConnector adapter is wired yet, so no wire-level exchange runs today
- Higher education (Phase 2): SURFconext federation, Studielink enrolment, OOAPI 5.0 catalog, eduPersonAffiliation, edubadges
- Assessment authoring (Phase 3): proctored exams (ProctoringProviderInterface for ProctorU, Honorlock, ExamSoft — interface only, no provider wired), EDCI verifiable credentials
- cmi5/xAPI learning-record ingest: the xAPI-statement schema and its lifecycle hook exist, but there is no learner-facing LRS ingest endpoint yet and cmi5 AU launch-token minting is a documented, currently-disabled stub (tracked in openspec/changes/cmi5-xapi-lrs-ingest/)
- AI-assisted features (Phase 5): adaptive learning paths + AI item generation, gated behind EU AI Act high-risk feature flags

**Technical foundations**

- Built on OpenRegister (data layer), OpenConnector (external system adapters), and @conduction/nextcloud-vue
- Content runtime target: cmi5 + xAPI primary, SCORM 1.2 / 2004 compatibility shim (learner-facing ingest and cmi5 launch not yet wired — see Later phases)
- Immutable audit trail backs compliance evidence, AVG record-of-processing, and AI Act decision traces
- Standards-first: 26 standards mapped (SCORM, xAPI, cmi5, LTI, QTI, EDCI, Open Badges 3.0, UWLR, OSO, ROD, Edukoppeling, SchoolID, ECK iD, SURFconext, AVG, EU AI Act, BIO2, NIS2) — most as design target, not all yet implemented

Free and open source under the EUPL-1.2 license.

**Support:** support@conduction.nl
    ]]></description>
    <description lang="nl"><![CDATA[Scholiq combineert een leerlingvolgsysteem (LVS) voor primair, voortgezet en hoger onderwijs met een leeromgeving / LMS voor corporate L&D en overheidstrainingen.

**v0.1 wedge — Compliance-training**

- Jaarlijkse AVG / BIO / NIS2 / Cyberbeveiligingswet herhalingstraining
- Bulk-inschrijving van alle medewerkers in verplichte trainingen
- Ondertekende attestaties per leerling vastleggen
- Detectie van aankomende verloopdata van certificaten
- Realtime dekkingspercentage per regelgeving
- Audit-pack export met onveranderlijk evidence-logboek
- Bulkregistratie van extern gevolgde trainingen, met officiersverificatie en gekoppelde certificaatuitgifte
- Wizard voor schooljaarovergang (voorstel + side-effect-vrije preview)
- Import van IMS QTI 2.x/3.0- en Common Cartridge-itembanken
- Uitgifte en publieke verificatie van Open Badges 3.0-credentials

**Latere fasen**

- K-12 leerlingvolgsysteem (Fase 2): BRON/ROD, UWLR, OSO, Edukoppeling, SchoolID/ECK iD-pseudonimisatie, OPP-cyclus, PTA-beoordeling, DigiD-ouderflow — er bestaat al een generieke data-uitwisselingswachtrij met een OSO-ouderakkoordstap, maar er is nog geen BRON/ROD-, OSO- of SURFconext-OpenConnector-adapter gekoppeld, dus er loopt nog geen daadwerkelijke uitwisseling
- Hoger onderwijs (Fase 2): SURFconext-federatie, Studielink-inschrijving, OOAPI 5.0-catalogus, eduPersonAffiliation, edubadges
- Toetsing (Fase 3): proctored exams (alleen interface, nog geen gekoppelde provider), EDCI verifieerbare credentials
- cmi5/xAPI-leerregistratie: het xAPI-statement-schema en de bijbehorende lifecycle-hook bestaan, maar er is nog geen leerling-gerichte LRS-ingest-endpoint en het aanmaken van cmi5-launchtokens is een gedocumenteerde, momenteel uitgeschakelde stub (zie openspec/changes/cmi5-xapi-lrs-ingest/)
- AI-functies (Fase 5): adaptieve leerpaden, gegate achter EU AI Act high-risk feature flags

Vrij en open source onder de EUPL-1.2-licentie.

**Ondersteuning:** support@conduction.nl
    ]]></description>
    <version>0.2.13</version>
    <licence>EUPL-1.2</licence>
    <author mail="info@conduction.nl" homepage="https://www.conduction.nl/">Conduction</author>
    <namespace>Scholiq</namespace>
    <documentation>
        <user>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq</user>
        <admin>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq</admin>
        <developer>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq</developer>
    </documentation>
    <category>tools</category>
    <website>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq</website>
    <discussion>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq/discussions</discussion>
    <bugs>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq/issues</bugs>
    <repository>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/nextcloud-scholiq</repository>

    <screenshot>https://codeberg.org/Conduction/scholiq/raw/branch/main/img/app-store.svg</screenshot>

    <!--
        AVG Art. 30 verwerkingsregister consumes OpenRegister's per-access
        read-logging capability (the x-openregister-processing dialect,
        ProcessingLogService / ProcessingLogController, and the
        /api/avg/verwerkingen[/betrokkene] endpoints). That capability ships
        from OpenRegister >= 0.2.14. The minimum is also recorded as the
        `openregister` constraint in lib/Settings/scholiq_register.json.
    -->
    <dependencies>
        <app>openregister</app>
        <app>openconnector</app>
        <nextcloud min-version="32" max-version="34"/>
        <php min-version="8.3" max-version="8.4"/>
    </dependencies>

    <navigations>
        <navigation>
            <id>scholiq</id>
            <name>Scholiq</name>
            <route>scholiq.page.index</route>
            <icon>app.svg</icon>
        </navigation>
    </navigations>

    <repair-steps>
        <install>
            <step>OCA\Scholiq\Repair\InitializeSettings</step>
            <!-- ADR-023: seed the action-authorization matrix (default admin-only). -->
            <step>OCA\Scholiq\Repair\InitializeActions</step>
        </install>
        <post-migration>
            <step>OCA\Scholiq\Repair\InitializeSettings</step>
            <!-- ADR-023: seed the action-authorization matrix (default admin-only). -->
            <step>OCA\Scholiq\Repair\InitializeActions</step>
        </post-migration>
    </repair-steps>

    <settings>
        <admin>OCA\Scholiq\Settings\AdminSettings</admin>
        <admin-section>OCA\Scholiq\Sections\SettingsSection</admin-section>
    </settings>
</info>
